<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><title>travelingmaterials</title><link href="http://travelingmaterials.github.io/" rel="alternate"></link><link href="http://travelingmaterials.github.io/feeds/all.atom.xml" rel="self"></link><id>http://travelingmaterials.github.io/</id><updated>2018-03-20T10:20:00-06:00</updated><entry><title>New Zealand Day 3</title><link href="http://travelingmaterials.github.io/new-zealand-day-3.html" rel="alternate"></link><published>2018-03-20T10:20:00-06:00</published><updated>2018-03-20T10:20:00-06:00</updated><author><name>rebecca reitz</name></author><id>tag:travelingmaterials.github.io,2018-03-20:/new-zealand-day-3.html</id><summary type="html">&lt;h2&gt;On the Bright Side, Waterfalls&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;My Fitbit claims I only got 5.5 hours of sleep last night, which may be part of why I've been viewing the day thgouh a haze of drowsiness. There was no helping this situation, we got back from the glowworm caves a little after …&lt;/p&gt;</summary><content type="html">&lt;h2&gt;On the Bright Side, Waterfalls&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;My Fitbit claims I only got 5.5 hours of sleep last night, which may be part of why I've been viewing the day thgouh a haze of drowsiness. There was no helping this situation, we got back from the glowworm caves a little after 9:30 last night and we had to wake up at 4:30 am in order to complete a two hour drive before checking in to another boat ride at 7:00 am this morning. We were supposed to do a boat/kayak tour of the Milford Sound this morning, but we were informed on arrival that the trip was canceled due to the rain.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Instead, we took that tour guide's recommendation to wait for the sun to rise and then catch one of the smaller boat-based nature tours of the Milford Sound in order to see the waterfalls in the area. "They'll all be gushing, today," he promised us.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img alt="waiting for the sun" src="images/nz014.jpg"&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I'd been resistant to the idea of doing a boat tour for a long while. They are commonly listed as the thing to do in Fjordlands, but I generally am miserably sea sick on boats and only tolerate them as a means of getting to an activity I prefer (ie diving). But I took two Dramamine (the less drowsy kind, but this still contributes to the sleepiness) and rolled with it. On the bright side, the guide was right. There were waterfalls everywhere and they were indeed gushing.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I don't quite know how to choose the photos to illustrate this properly. But imagine, if you will, a pretty standard waterfall. Like this one.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img alt="some kind of waterfall" src="images/nz015.jpg"&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Now just copy paste it at least five times onto every surface you can see.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img alt="so many waterfalls" src="images/nz019.jpg"&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Everywhere. There were waterfalls everywhere. The boat had good commentary and would get playfully close to some of the falls, allowing the people on board to take selfies with the falls and feel the spray. Ian had a great time. And I was, to their credit, pretty comfortable. They had lots of free coffee to stave off the tired, a partially covered top-level where you cower from the rain and occasionally venture out to take a photo, and a really cushion cabin.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We had gotten on one of the earliest boats of the day, so it was still only 11 am when we got back to the docks. It was still pouring, so Ian and I decided to stick to the shortest hikes (&amp;lt;1 hour each) on our way back to Te Anau with an emphasis on anything with a waterfall. This was not a choosy selection criterion because, as I may have mentioned, there were waterfalls anywhere there could possibly be waterfalls.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img alt="marian waterfall" src="images/nz017.jpg"&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Fjordlands apparently gets around 240 rainy days a year, so its hikes are built for rain. There are wooden boards with metal meshes over them (to prevent you from slipping) in every place there may be a temporary creek, and on the most common short hikes there's some degree of coverage from above as well.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img alt="ian enjoying the rainforest" src="images/nz016.jpg"&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We also had all of the proper gear (rain jacket, rain pants, and waterproof boots), so we had a good time wandering in this rain forest. Occasionally we were rewarding with moments where the skies would clear up a little and present us with spectacular views (of more waterfalls).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img alt="becca and waterfall" src="images/nz018.jpg"&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Eventually we made our way back to our temporary home in Te Anau, where we took a long nap.&lt;/p&gt;</content><category term="New Zealand"></category></entry><entry><title>New Zealand Day 2</title><link href="http://travelingmaterials.github.io/new-zealand-day-2.html" rel="alternate"></link><published>2018-03-19T10:20:00-06:00</published><updated>2018-03-19T10:20:00-06:00</updated><author><name>rebecca reitz</name></author><id>tag:travelingmaterials.github.io,2018-03-19:/new-zealand-day-2.html</id><summary type="html">&lt;h2&gt;That Sunrise, Man&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I woke up at 6:30 am because that's the normally when I wake up and apparently I am a perfectly calibrated clock with no jet lag. This was just in time to get blown away by the ludicrous sunrise that was happening just outside the AirBNB …&lt;/p&gt;</summary><content type="html">&lt;h2&gt;That Sunrise, Man&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I woke up at 6:30 am because that's the normally when I wake up and apparently I am a perfectly calibrated clock with no jet lag. This was just in time to get blown away by the ludicrous sunrise that was happening just outside the AirBNB. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img alt="sunrise animated" src="images/nzsunrise.gif"&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We sat out on the patio and slowly ate our breakfast while watching the colors slowly change. The people from the other nearby units also started making their way out onto the patio to see the show. It was a wonderful way to start the day.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img alt="sunrise selfy" src="images/nz010.jpg"&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;As the sun finally started to peak out from behind the mountains the rain kicked up. We went inside to repack our bags and then drove up to Queenstown Hill to go for a quick hike.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img alt="queentown hill" src="images/nz012.jpg"&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The Queenstown Hill hike is a very pleasant activity for an intermittently rainy day. Much of the hike is very shaded and provides some moderate shelter from the rain, there are fun informational signs, and you get a great view from the top if the conditions permit. The signs explain that this hill is sacred to the Maori and discuss the history of the region and the ongoing conservation efforts in the area. For example, see the dead trees in the background of these photographs? Those are called Wildings, they're an invasive species, and they are being killed off on purpose. You're encouraged to just pull the seedlings out of the ground if you see one near the path.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img alt="becca and the mountains" src="images/nz013.jpg"&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We then got brunch at Joe's Garage in Queentown and took the mildly windy road out to Te Anau. There we checked into our next home and spent the rainy afternoon watching TV and making grilled cheese sandwiches (with tomato soup).&lt;/p&gt;</content><category term="New Zealand"></category></entry><entry><title>New Zealand Day 1</title><link href="http://travelingmaterials.github.io/new-zealand-day-1.html" rel="alternate"></link><published>2018-03-18T10:20:00-06:00</published><updated>2018-03-18T10:20:00-06:00</updated><author><name>rebecca reitz</name></author><id>tag:travelingmaterials.github.io,2018-03-18:/new-zealand-day-1.html</id><summary type="html">&lt;h2&gt;The Long Night&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img alt="luggage" src="images/nz002.jpg"&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We entered San Jose’s airport at around 4 pm on the afternoon of the 16th and left Queenstown’s airport at around 1 pm on the afternoon of the 18th. In between, we got to hang out at the San Jose airport lounge, had three flights …&lt;/p&gt;</summary><content type="html">&lt;h2&gt;The Long Night&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img alt="luggage" src="images/nz002.jpg"&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We entered San Jose’s airport at around 4 pm on the afternoon of the 16th and left Queenstown’s airport at around 1 pm on the afternoon of the 18th. In between, we got to hang out at the San Jose airport lounge, had three flights (which were all delayed either leaving or getting to their gate), crossed the dateline (so we completely missed the 17th), and had to have our hiking boots cleaned by New Zeland border patrol.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img alt="ready" src="images/nz003.jpg"&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We'd both had some pretty stressful weeks leading up to this vacation, so I think we started the flights feeling a little more tense than usual. But ultimately everything went totally fine and I really just want to show you some pictures that we took out the airplane window during landing. New Zealand is truly as beautiful as advertised. It's just stunning.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img alt="auckland" src="images/nz004.jpg"&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Here's Auckland&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Queenstown, in particular, has these dramatic steep mountains, lush hills, and clear blue lake that just looks painted on. It’s nonsense beautiful.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img alt="queenstown1" src="images/nz005.jpg"&gt;
&lt;em&gt;And here's Queenstown&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img alt="queenstown2" src="images/nz006.jpg"&gt;
&lt;em&gt;And here's the view from our AirBNB. It's bonkers pretty.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;So we picked up the rental car, drove into town (on the left side of the road, mind you, which even after a day still fells deeply wrong), ate some savory lamb pies, checked into our AirBNB for a quick rest, and bought some groceries.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img alt="rose garden" src="images/nz007.jpg"&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;And then it was back into town to tour the public gardens, eat a nice Polynesian dinner, and take a lot more photos. I can’t get over how amazingly crazy beautiful this place is.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img alt="sunset by the lake" src="images/nz008.jpg"&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img alt="sunset lake" src="images/nz009.jpg"&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</content><category term="New Zealand"></category></entry><entry><title>New Zealand Day 0</title><link href="http://travelingmaterials.github.io/new-zealand-day-0.html" rel="alternate"></link><published>2018-03-16T10:20:00-06:00</published><updated>2018-03-16T10:20:00-06:00</updated><author><name>rebecca reitz</name></author><id>tag:travelingmaterials.github.io,2018-03-16:/new-zealand-day-0.html</id><summary type="html">&lt;h2&gt;Just you wait&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img alt="waiting" src="images/nz001.jpg"&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I've met up with Ian and packed our bags and we're finally headed to New Zealand. It's a country that I've wanted to visit for a long time and it's the first international trip that I'm taking with Ian alone so we should be in for a …&lt;/p&gt;</summary><content type="html">&lt;h2&gt;Just you wait&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img alt="waiting" src="images/nz001.jpg"&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I've met up with Ian and packed our bags and we're finally headed to New Zealand. It's a country that I've wanted to visit for a long time and it's the first international trip that I'm taking with Ian alone so we should be in for a fun ride. We're road tripping along the West coast of the South Island of New Zealand, starting at Queentown and eventually making our way up to Nelson. Here's the day by day plan for this New Zealand trip.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt;We hop on a plane on the 16th but we won't land until the 18th. So we immediately lose
a couple of days during our 13.5 hour flight from Los Angeles to Auckland&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;We take a flight from Auckland to Queenstown - so we'll arrive at our first true
destination in New Zealand around noon on the 18th. We'll then pick up our rental car,
buy some groceries, and spend the day exploring Queenstown. We have a reservation at the
Blue Kanu in the evening.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Hike near Queenstown in the morning, drive to Te Anau in the afternoon, and visit the Te Anau Glowworm caves in the evening.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Spend the full day hiking in Fjordlands&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Drive up to the area surrounding Fox Glacier (this is the longest drive in this trip) and settle into our temporary home in Okarito&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Hike in Tai Poutini all day&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Do some sightseeing along the drive to our next place at Tutaki&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Hike the Mt Robert Circuit in Nelson Lakes National Park and make our way to Nelson for a nice dinner in the city&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Rent a bike and cycle the great taste trail&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Fly to Auckland, do a walking tour, be tourists in New Zealand's LA-equivalent sprawling city&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Fly back to the USA and part ways&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;</content><category term="New Zealand"></category></entry></feed>